Guide to the Archie Ammons papers,1945-2010.
Ammons, Archie papers, 1945-2010.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Archie Ammons papers, 1945-2010.
14-12-2665
A. R. Ammons 1926-2001
26.4 Cubic Feet.
Journals, correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, chapbooks, typescript, memoranda, and paintings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Primarily incoming correspondence from students and teaching colleagues; fellow literary figures; and family members. The letters frequently enclose poetry for review; snapshots of family members; and photos of Ammons and other literary figures. The papers provide sources for the study of modern American poetry, including the publication of poetry in various journals. Some letters discuss the publication of Ammons' own books of poetry; others highlight activities of small presses. Letters and records of writers' conferences underscore Ammons' role in Southern regional literature. Also, material detailing his role in Cornell's Department of English and its creative writing program.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Poet and university professor Archie Randolph Ammons was born near Whiteville, N.C., in 1926. He earned a reputation as one of the nation's leading poets in the decades after he joined the Cornell University faculty in 1963, becoming Goldwin Smith Professor of Poetry a decade later. Recipient of the Bollingen Prize and the National Book Award and Critics Circle Award for poetry, Ammons was one of the first recipients of a MacArthur Foundation fellowship in 1981.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Primarily incoming correspondence from students and teaching colleagues; fellow poets and other literary figures; and a few family members. The letters frequently enclose chapbooks and typescript or manuscript poetry for review; snapshots of family members; and formal and informal photographs of Ammons and other literary figures. Envelopes frequently bear Ammons' draft replies to letters received as well as draft poetry, lecture notes, and other matter. The papers provide sources for the study of modern American poetry, including the publication of poetry in journals such as The Hudson Review, The Manhattan Review, and The Bluefish; and in such Southern literary journals as The Pembroke Magazine and The North Carolina Literary Review. Letters from W. W. Norton & Company discuss the publication of Ammons' own books of poetry, while others highlight activities of such small presses as Palaemon Press Limited and the Jackpine Press. Letters and records of writers conferences sponsored at the Reynolds Homestead Learning Center in Critz, Va., underscore Ammons' role in Southern regional literature. Letters, departmental memoranda, and "Recommendations" files detail his role in Cornell's Department of English and its creative writing program. And letters from 1981 and later record his relationship with the MacArthur Foundation.
Also included are sixty-eight journals, in which Ammons interfiled journal entries, poems, and correspondence. They detail Ammons' growth as a poet, and his relationship with his mentor Josephine Miles and editor John Benedict. Literary manuscripts include published and unpublished poetry.
Journal #1, Journal (letters to Phyllis) 1947-1949, photographs: Archie and son John, Archie and grandson, Archie.
Correspondence, 1997-1998; Over 50 watercolor paintings dating from the late 1970s to the late 1980s.
Major correspondents include John G. Benedict, James Bertolino, Philip E. Booth, Frederick Buell, David Burak, James Burgess, Kathryn Stripling Byer, Stephen Cushman, Ephim Fogel, Kenneth Frazelle, Philip H. Fried, Alice Fulton, William Harmon, David Ardene Hinton, Josephine Jacobsen, Phyllis Janowitz, Cathrael Kazin, Milton Kessler, David Lehman, Gay Leonhardt, Michael McFee, Jim Merod, Frederick Morgan, Reeve Parker, Robert Dale Schultz, John E. Sitter, Mark Soifer, Stephen Tapscott, Helen Hennessy Vendler, Hugh Walthall, Emily Herring Wilson, and Stuart Wright.
Archie Ammons art shows (2008-2010)
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ammons, A. R.,1926-; Benedict, John G.; Bertolino, James, 1942-; Booth, Philip E.; Buell, Frederick, 1942-; Burak, David, 1945-; Burgess, James.; Byer, Kathryn Stripling.; Cushman, Stephen, 1956-; Fogel, Ephim, 1920-1992.; Frazelle, Kenneth.; Fried, Philip, 1945-; Fulton, Alice, 1952-; Harmon, William, 1938-; Hinton, David, 1954-; Jacobsen, Josephine.; Janowitz, Phyllis.; Kazin, Cathrael.; Kessler, Milton.; Lehman, David, 1948-; Leonhardt, Gay.; McFee, Michael.; McNamara, Charles B.; Merod, Michael.; Miles, Josephine, 1911-; Morgan, Frederick, 1922-; Parker, Reeve.; Schultz, Robert Dale, 1951-; Sitter, John E.; Soifer, Mark.; Tapscott, Stephen, 1948-; Vendler, Helen Hennessy.; Walthall, Hugh, 1948-; Wilson, Emily Herring.; Wright, Stuart T.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. English Dept.; Cornell University. Goldwin Smith Professorship.; John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation.; Reynolds Homestead Continuing Education Center.; W. W. Norton & Company.
Titles:
Hudson review.; Manhattan review.; Bluefish.; Pembroke magazine.; North Carolina literary review.
Subjects:
National Book Awards.; American poetry.; American poetry--Publishing.; Poetry--Study and teaching.; Little presses.; Poetry, Modern.; Poets, American.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Poems; Watercolors.; Paintings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only. Researchers may view one folder at a time.
Box 130 is closed until 2033 or by permission of John Ammons
SERIES LIST
Series I. Journals
1. Numbered, nos. 1-68 (1952 to 1992)
Boxes 7-25
2. Un-numbered (24 journals, 1964 to 1988, 1949-1985)
Boxes 26-27, 125
Series II. Poetry File
Boxes 28-29, 112
Series III. Personal Records
Box 30, 116, 121, 124
Series IV. Correspondence
1.Unidentified Correspondents, A-W
Boxes 31-32 (fold. 1-2)
2.Correspondence with Family Members
Boxes 32 (fold. 3-5)-33, 113
3.Other Correspondence, A-Z
Boxes 34-55
4.Correspondence, 1997-2000
Box 114
5.Correspondence, [1974] 1997-2001, A-Z
Box 119
6.Condolences
Box 120
Series V. Literary Manuscripts
1. Published
a. Collections of Poems
Boxes 56-62 (fold. 1-2)
b. Poems Appearing in Magazines
Box 62 (fold. 3-6)
c. Other Writings
Box 63
2. Unpublished
a. Loose Poems
Boxes 64-75, 122
b. Grouped Poems
Boxes 76-79, 122
c. Bound Poems
Boxes 80-83
d. Other Unpublished Writings
Box 84 (fold. 1-6)
3. Combined Published and Unpublished or Unknown
Box 122-124
Series VI. Professional Activities
Box 84 (fold. 7-21)
Series VII. Broadcasts, Recordings, and Readings
Boxes 124, 126, 128, 132, C-14-15, C-18
Series VIII. Awards
Box 85, 116, 118, 121
Series IX. Critical Reception
1. Essays and Articles
Boxes 86-87, 122
2. Clippings (articles, reviews)
Box 88, 121
3. Ads for Events or Publications
Box 89, 123
Series X. Writings and Works by Others
Boxes 90-92, 116
Series XI. Photographs, Memorabilia, and Artwork
Boxes 93-97, 115-117, 124, 129, 131, map case folder 1
Series XII. Books and Magazines
1. Works by A.R. Ammons (poetry, essays)
Boxes 98-99, 100-105, 133
2. Works about A. R. Ammons (criticism, reviews, interviews, Ph.D. Thesis, posthumous compilations)
Boxes 98-99, 106-108
3. Works inscribed to A.R. Ammons
Boxes 109-111
Series XIII. Phyllis Ammons' Files
Boxes 98, 116, 127, 129-130
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Journals
  An index to the contents of the journals is available here.
  - Numbered
    - no. 2-5, May 5, 1952 to August 15, 1952 (Box 7)
    - no. 6-10, June 10, 1952 to November 14, 1954 (Box 8)
    - no. 11-16, February 12, 1955 to June 5, 1957 (Box 9)
    - no. 17-22, June 11, 1957 to October 25, 1958 (Box 10)
    - no. 23-28, November 10, 1958 to November 6, 1960 (Box 11)
    - no. 29-32, November 10, 1960 to May 2, 1962 (Box 12)
    - no. 33-36, May 13, 1962 to September 30, 1963 (Box 13)
    - no. 37-40, October 7, 1963 to December 21, 1964 (Box 14)
    - no. 41-43 [part I], January 5, 1965 to April 7, 1966 (Box 15)
    - no. 43 [part II] - 45, November 22, 1966 to February 29, 1968 (Box 16)
    - no. 46-48, August 23, 1968 to August 16, 1969 (Box 17)
    - no. 49-51, August 14, 1969 to November 14, 1970 (Box 18)
    - no. 52-53, November 17, 1970 to January 3, 1972 (Box 19)
    - no. 54-55, December 17, 1971 to October 8, 1972 (Box 20)
    - no. 56-58, June 9, 1973 to February 23, 1976 (Box 21)
    - no. 59-60, September 30, 1975 to December 18, 1977 (Box 22)
    - no. 61-62, January 25, 1978 to December 19, 1983 (Box 23)
    - no. 63-65, October 29, 1982 to December 31, 1986 (Box 24)
    - no. 66-68, January 5, 1987-March 4, 1992 (Box 25)
  - Un-numbered Journals
    - 15 notebooks and composition books of various sizes, various dates (Box 26)
    - 9 notebooks and composition books of various sizes, various dates (Box 27)
    - loose pages, 1949-1985 (Box 125, Folder 1-6)
- Series II. Poetry Files
  - 5" x 3" cards, letters A to Mc (Box 28, Folder 1-18)
  - 5" x 3" cards, letters M to W (Box 29, Folder 19-35)
  - Index cards A-Z (Box 112)
- Series III. Personal Records
  - Business records pertaining to the Amhill Corporation, 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Amhill Corporation embosser, undated; MU-1255 (Box MU Box 68)
  - Business records pertaining to the Amhill Corporation, 1963-1964 (Box 68)
  - Transcript issued to Archie Ammons by Wake Forest College, print from microfilm, 30-May-49 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Driver's license issued to Archie R. Ammons by New York State (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - High school yearbook and reunion materials, 1943, 1949, 1972 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - High school yearbook and reunion materials, 1943 and 1993 (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - Poetry payments, 1968-1971 (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - Poetry payments, 1972-1995 (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - The 1949 Howler, Wake Forest College Yearbook, 1949 (Box 124)
- Series IV. Correspondence
  - Unidentified Correspondents
    - Unidentified Correspondents, general (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, A-B (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, C (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, D-E (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, F-I (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, J-K (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, L-P (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, R-W (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Family Members
    - Mother (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Cox, Vida (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Cox, Vida (cont'd) (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "dad" and Blanche (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - John (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Gail (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Mona (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Phyllis (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Phyllis from Archie, 1947-1949 (Box 113)
    - Other family members (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Other Correspondence, A-Z
    - Abrams, Douglas and Peggy (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Abrams, Mike (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Abraxas (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Academy of American Poets, March 26, 1969-June 13, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Ackerman, Diane, May 9, 1972-February 14, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Adams - America Singing! (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, June 6, 1967-September 29, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - American Poetry Review, April 9, 1974-February 3, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - American Printing House for the Blind - American Scholar (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - American Writers Against Nuclear Energy - Arant (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Aries One - Basquette-Baal (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Bath - Beloit College (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Beloit Poetry Journal, March 15, 1975 - June 1, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Benedikt, Michael - Berry, Wendell (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Bertolino, James and Lois, December 11, 1993 - December 1996 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Bethell, Tim - Bloom, Carol Ann (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Bloom, Harold, n.d., August 21, 1969-November 6, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Bly, Robert - Blumenthal, Michael (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - BOA Editions, June 20, 1978 - Oct 17, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Bock, Fred - Bommarito, Angela (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Bond, Cynthia (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Bonnette, Peter - Bookery (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Booth, Philip, December 5, 1994- August 5, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards, April 16 & 22, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Boston Critic - Brendstetter, Elizabeth (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Brandt, Florence (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Brantley, R. - Bryson, John (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Buell, Fred, December 21, 1970 - January 10, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Bukowski, Charles, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Bullis, Jerry, November 1, 1971 - March 13, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Burak, David, July 31, 1974 - March 1997 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Burbank, Michael - Byer, Kay (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Cabalquinto, Louis - Centolella, Tom (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - The Charlotte Obsrever - Chase, Karen (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Chelsea, May 30, 1963-February 19, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Chenkin, Dana - Chestnutt, Thurman (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Chicago Review, n.d., January 7, 1965-August 1975 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Chock, Laurie - Coleman, Dan (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Coleman, Elliott, n.d., February 1960-December 14, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Columbia Historical Society - Cornell, Lorna (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Cornell University (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Board of Trustees, June 6, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Campus Store, February 28, 1974-September 25, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Career Center, November 21, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - College of Arts and Sciences, February 19, 1969-February 14, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Cornell Review, November 16, 1977-June 11, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Cornell University, n.d., September 6, 1974-January 6, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Department of Anthropology, September 30, 1974-February 17, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Department of Chemistry, March 10, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Department of Comparative Literature, October 26, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Department of English, March 7, 1969-April 9, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Department of Entomology and Limnology, July 18, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Department of German Literature, February 19, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Glee Club, November 18, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - The Graduate School, June 23 1969-May 20 1970 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - The Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, [September?] 1977; January 14, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Libraries, January 28, 1969-January 19, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Office of Alumni Affairs; Office of the Chancellor; Office of the President; Office of Public Information; Personnel Department / Human Resources; Phi Beta Kappa Society; Program of Science, Technology, and Society; Society for the Humanitites; June 3 and July 19, 1996; March 30 and May 4, 1978; September 25, 1969-December 9, 1993; May 12, 1969-March 31, 1975; June 21, 1971-May 15, 1995; March 28 and April 3, 1969; March 4 and 7, 1974; November 27, 1972-March 30, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - The University Faculty;University Press; Wellness Program; Women's Studies Program, December 2, 1993-July 10, 1995; July 10, 1967-October 19, 1993; January 15, 1993; April 29, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Cotton, Nancy - Cushman, Sandra (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Cushman, Steve, April 9, 1979-March 29, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Cutler, Richard - Davis, Sylvia (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Decade - Di Santo, Grace (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Discourse - Durner, Eve (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - East Carlina University - Emblen, Donald (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Emmerich, Karen - Enlow, Julie (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Epoch, undated, May 26, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Epstein, Judi - Evans, Jennie (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Fairleigh Dickinson University - Felderman, Eric (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Fellowship of Southern Writers, December 6, 1989-January 6, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - The Ferguson Library (Stamford, CT) - Firlik, Andrew D. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Fogel, Ephim, undated, October 2, 1970-August 7, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Fogel, Ephim (cont'd), February 26, 1973-August 14, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Ford, William - Forum (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Fosso, Doyle, undated, November 2, 1974-September 9, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Foster, Thomas E. - Frankowski, Ray (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Frazelle, Kenneth, March 7, 1976-March 13, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Freeman, Jane, November 14, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 3B)
      Response to a letter of appreciation about his poetry, mentions his interest in watercolors. With envelope.
    - W. H. Freeman & Co. - Fried, Debra (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Fried, Philip, April 2, 1979-September 29, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Friedberg, Martha - Fulks, Bryan (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Fulton, Alice, September 22, 1985-December 27, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Gale Research - Gershkovich, Roman (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Gerstman, Eric Lee - Givens, Paul R. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Gladding, Jody - Gnomon Press (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Gobel, Doris - Goodwin, Joy (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Gossette, Louise and Tom, March 9, 1975-December 29, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Graham, ? - Gushing, Laura J. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Hahan, Robert - Harcourt, Brace & World (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Harmon, William, July 3, 1974-March 2, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Harp, Nicholas - Harrow. Leslie (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Hart Publishing Co. - Hastings, Chris (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Hathaway, Baxter, February 7, 1969-December 22, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Hathaway, Kit - Hinman, William (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Hinton, David, August 28, 1992-October 21, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Hobart and William Smith Colleges - Hoffman, Jan (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Hoffman, Roald, December 20, 1986-March 5, 1997 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Holder, Alan - Houston, University of. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Howard, Edward - Hudson, Joanna (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Hudson Review, February 6, 1963-February 4, 1997 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Huebsch, Jason - Hyatt, Charles (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Ingari, Frank - Ithaca High School (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Jackpine Press, February 12, 1976-July 12, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Jacobsen, Josephine, January 1959-October 6, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Jackson, Herb W. - Janes, Kelly (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Janowitz, Phyllis, July 21, 1985 - August 3, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Janowitz, Tama - Johnson, J. G. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Johnson, Nate - Juscik, Steve (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Kahle, G. R. - Kenstetter, Bob (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Kahn, Alfred E. ("Mountain Talk" 1972, By Archie Ammons) (Box 43, Folder 8B)
    - Kheradi, Delara - Khalip, Jacques (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Kessler, Milton, March 1964 - March 6, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Kilgore, C. Judson - Koehlar, Stanley (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Kooistra, John - Kuyira, Greg (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Landau, Joe - Legler, Philip (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Lehman, David, May 24, 1971-April 21, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Leighton, Betty - Lewis, George M. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Library of Congress - Loess Hills Books (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Logan, John, September 20, 1956-January 15, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Lohn, Jeffrey - Lyttle, David (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - MacArthur Foundation, October 21, 1988 and October 23, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - MacHammond, ? - Manfredi, Jeff (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Review, February 26, 1994 - May 19, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan Theatre Club - Maxwell School (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - McAleavey, David - McBride, Richard (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - McCall, Dan, January 29, 1977 - April 28, 1995 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - McClane, Genevieve (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - McClane, Kenneth, January 5, 1974 - January 22, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - McCloskey, Mark - McCollum, Stephen (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - McConkey, James, January 14, 1969 - May 31, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - McCown, Clint - McCoy, Maureen (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - McFee, Michael, December 12, 1979 - November 2, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - McGovern, Robert - Melack, Erica Ann (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Mead, Jane, n.d. September 4, 1996 - February 18, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Mermin, Dorothy, n.d., September 13, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Mermin, William (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Merod, James, n.d., 1974-1975 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Merrill, James - Miami, University of. (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - University of Michigan Press, May 23, 1994-April 19, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Michigan Review Quarterly, March 14, 1978-June 6, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Michigan, University of - Mikus, Eleanore (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Miles, Josephine, February 2, 1953-March 1978 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Miller, Emily - Mitato, Joe (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Mize, Ray - Morgan, [Buffy?] (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Morgan, Frederick, January 17, 1972-November 30, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Morgan, Robert, September 8, 1974-June 12, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Morley, Hilda - Nash, Millie (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - The Nation (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - The National Book Foundation - Nichols, Michael Garrrison (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Nimis, John F. - Northeastern University Press (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Norton & Norton, December 17, 1969-October 26, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Norton & Norton (cont'd), June 18, 1980-March 5, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Not Man Apart - The News & Observer (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina Literary Review, November 5, 1992-July 30, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - North Carolina, University Press (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Ohio Review, August 1974-December 6, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Ohio State University Press - Okazachi, Kaichi (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Okrent, Jill - Owens, Ann (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Pack, Robert - Paintbrush (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Palaemon Press, November 17, 1977-November 4, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Palmer, Patsy - Pantheon Books (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Paris Review, October 21, 1993-June 29, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Parker, James (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Parker, Reeve, March 11-22, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Partato, John (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Partisan Review, 1959, July 7, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Passaic County Community College - Pembroke Magazine (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Pembroke State University, May 25, 1993-April 21, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - PEN American Center - Phillips Exeter Academy (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Piasecki, Bruce (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Pierce, Richard - Plourde, Bruce (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Poets & Writers, February 5, 1971-April 17, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Poetry (Chicago) See also: Ruth Lilly Poetry Prize, November 1960-March 5, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Poetry Center, April 8, 1969-May 17, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Circuit of Ohio - Poetry Daily (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Poetry East, March 13, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Poetry Miscellany, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Poetry Northwest, May 5, 1964-March 7, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Seminar - Pratt, Charles (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Praxis, April 20-September 23, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Price, [?] - Purdum, Becky (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Quarterly Review of Literature, July 19, 1963-February 21, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Queens College - Quinn, Vincent (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Rabb, Peggy - [Rauff, Geo?] (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Ry, David, April 22, 1963-November 18, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Ray, Jan - Rev[e], Geoffrey (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Reynolda House Museum of American Art, July 25, 1975 and April 26, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation - Roman, Mike (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Roseliep, Raymond - Rudman, Mark (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Rushton, Rusty, June 23, 1994-August 27, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 19)